## Zoya Rani

Zoya.rani@aku.edu

House #202, Street#04, Sector8/A, Data Nagar, Orangi Town Karachi, Pakistan. Mobile No: +92335-2287477 Zoya--rani@hotmail.com Zoyarani25@gmail.com



SUBJECT APPLYING FOR POSITION OF MEDICAL TECHNOLOGIST

## **CARRER OBJECTIVE:**

To apply my functional knowledge and experience to enable effective contribution and thus establish myself as a capable Medical Technologist (Specialist in Molecular Pathology including Virology Bacteriology and Molecular Genetics).

Keep informed of new management and technical development and contribute to the growth of institute in turn help my growth and add to my knowledge.

## **EXPERIENCE:**

Work experiences details as follows,

June 2012 to July2012 Working as Trainee Technologist at Molecular

Pathology section of clinical laboratory at Liaquat National

University Hospital Karachi Pakistan.

Jan 2013 to Dec 2013 Working as Trainee Technologist at Clinical Laboratory

including HISTOPATHOLOGY, HEMATOLOGY,

MICROBIOLOGY, BIOCHEMISTRY, BLOOD BANK in

Aga Khan University Hospital Karachi Pakistan.

Jan 2014 to till date working as Staff Technologist at Molecular Pathology section of

clinical Laboratory at Aga Khan University Hospital Karachi

Pakistan.

## **Working Experience on Different Benches:**

Extensive Experience of optimizing & performing following test by PCR on routine basis,

#### VIRAL RNA/DNA BENCH

➤ Performing and reporting HCVPCR, HBVPCR, QHBV, QBKV, EBV PCR, and EGFR PCR.

#### • NAT TESTING

Performing and reporting NAT testing on Blood Donors for screening of HCV HBV and HIV.

## • NUCLEIC ACID EXTRACTION

➤ Nucleic acid (RNA and DNA) extraction and purification from different specimens by manual or automation (Ampliprep & Taqman)

### • AMPLIFICATION AND DETECTION

- ➤ PCR amplification, **Gel Electrophoresis** based detection.
- **Real Time PCR** processing and analysis and detection.

#### BACTERIOLOGY

Performing and reporting IGRA by manual ELISA method.

#### VIROLOGY

> Performing and reporting **DENIGM** by **ELISA** method.

## **INITIATIVES:**

• Optimization of EBV PCR on Real Time PCR with Dr Tariq Moatter.

## **TEAM WORKING:**

Worked effectively with colleagues in groups including planning, role, allocation, co-ordination and commitment.

## **EDUCATION:**

DEGREE	UNIVERSITY/ SUBJECT	YEAR OF PASSING	DIVISION/ POSITION
Bachelors of science (B.S)	UNIVERSITY OF KARACHI BIOTECHNOLOGY	2009-2012	1 <sup>ST</sup> DIVISION/ 3 <sup>RD</sup> POSITION
CERTIFICATE	INSTITUTE/ BOARD	YEAR OF PASSING	DIVISION
INTER (HSC)	SIR SYED GIRLS COLLEGE PRE-MEDICAL	2007-2008	1 <sup>ST</sup> DIVISION
MATRIC(SSC)	ROSE HOUSE GRAMMAR SCHOOL SCIENCE	2005-2006	1 <sup>ST</sup> DIVISION

# Training & Development Programs Of Aga khan University Hospital:

Taking following courses of T& OD.

- "Service Excellence" programme, 3 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga Khan University Karachi Pakistan...
- "Workplace Etiquettes" programme, 3 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga Khan University Karachi Pakistan.
- "Team Building" programme, 3 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga Khan University Karachi Pakistan...
- "Creating a Culture of Service Excellence" programme, 3 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga Khan University Karachi Pakistan...
- "Radiation protection for health care professionals" 4 Hour Course Conducted By, Department Of Continuing Professional Education, The Aga Khan University Hospital Karachi Pakistan.
- "Creating Right Impression" 4 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga Khan University Hospital Karachi Pakistan.
- "Skills For Successful Supervision" 4 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga Khan university Karachi Pakistan.
- "Chemical safety-MSDS & Spill Managment"4 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga Khan university Karachi Pakistan...
- "Time of your Life" 4 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga
  University Karachi Pakistan...
- "Manage your time effectively" 4 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga Khan university Karachi Pakistan...
- "Communication Skills" 4 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga Khan university Karachi Pakistan...
- "Fire Safety-prevention & Response" 4 hour course conducted by T& OD, The Aga Khan university Karachi Pakistan...
- "Introduction to JCIA" 4 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga Khan university Karachi Pakistan...
- "Service Excellence" programme, 4 hour course conducted by T&OD, The Aga Khan University Karachi Pakistan...
- "Biochemical Basis of Diabetes and Ageing" a lecture series conducted by Dr. Nessar Ahmed in Karachi university.

## **WORKSHOPS:**

- Facility Management and Safety, Radiation safety
- & Laboratory safety
- Patient Safety
- Violence Against Healthcare Workers
- Chemical safety-MSDS and Spill Management
- Fire safety-Prevention and response
- Introduction to JCIA (Joint Commission International Accreditation)
- Customer relationship in Strategies
- How to stay motivated at workplace
- Creating a culture of service excellence
- Introduction To ISO 9001:2008
- Workplace Etiquette

•

## **INSTRUMENT TRAINING:**

- Trained on, Cobas Ampliprep and Taqman for various applications of Molecular Pathology at The Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan.
- Trained on **Real Time PCR** (Light cycler, Rotor Gene) used for real time analysis.
- Isolation of **Prokaryotic** (**Bacterial**), **genomic DNA**, from Mononuclear Cells, Body Fluid, and Tissue Biopsies.
- **Viral DNA extraction** from Serum and Plasma by Viral Lysis Buffer, Viral RNA extraction of HCV by Ampliprep Lysis Reagents etc.
- Trained on **QIAGENE** for nucleic acid extraction.
- Trained on Cobas Taq man.
- Trained on Cobas Z480 system.
- Trained on Cobas LC480 system.

## **OTHER RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Assist in teaching/training of junior staff, Elective students and trainees.
- To check and monitor consumption of supplies on weekly basis.
- Participating with Joint Commission International Accreditation (JCIA) working group which strictly monitor the performance, according to standards of Joint Commission International Accreditation "JCIA"), from Molecular Pathology section, Clinical Laboratory, Aga Khan University Hospital
- Analyze laboratory findings to check the accuracy of the results.
- Operate, calibrate and maintain equipment used in quantitative and qualitative analysis, such as centrifuges, spectrophotometer, and computer-controlled analyzers like real-time PCR machines.
- Enter data from analysis of medical tests and clinical results into computer for storage. Establish and monitor programs to ensure the accuracy of laboratory results.
- Provide technical information about test results to physicians, members and researchers. Supervise, train, and direct lab assistants, laboratory technicians and medical students in areas of research.
- Delivering lectures to trainee technologists.
- Attended seminars on Quality Management system related to Molecular biology

## LANGUAGES:

Urdu

English.

Punjabi.

## **COMPUTER SKILLS:**

Microsoft Word.

Microsoft Excel.

Microsoft PowerPoint.

Internet browsing.

## **REFERENCES:**

## Dr. Tariq Moatter

Associate Professor

Head of department Molecular Pathology Section

Department of Pathology and Microbiology, Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi Pakistan.

Email: tariq.moatter@aku.edu

#### Dr Zahra Hasan

Associate Professor

Department of Pathology and Microbiology, Aga Khan University Hospital Karachi Pakistan.

Email: zahra.hasan@aku.edu

#### Dr.Israr nasir

Associate professor and HOD of the department of molecular pathology liaquat national hospital Karachi Pakistan

Email: Dr.MIsrar.Nasir@lnh.edu.pk